what's up 2x Karma storms this is Nick
at bobbend.com with a video for the
ladies on the best pre-workouts for
women the questions we need to answer in
this video is why would you want to take
a pre-workout and also is there such a
thing as a pre-workout for women like do
you really need different ingredients
before I go on I should make it clear
this is like for legal reasons but also
ethical and medical reasons I'm not a
doctor right so I'm not a medical
professional if you are going to make
significant changes to your exercise or
your dietary or your supplement regimen
you should speak to your own doctor
before before doing so you know you
might have medications that interact
with this or that you might have prior
conditions I don't know but let's not
talk about the best pre-workouts
foreign
[Music]
so when talking about the best
pre-workouts I'll give you guys a little
peek behind the curtain here the way
this works is people ask us for
recommendations for a wide variety of
different kinds of pre-workouts and a
lot of the time the answer is the same
products right so for example the best
pre-workout overall the best value
pre-workout the best tasting pre-workout
and the best for endurance it's all the
same product in our opinion like this
product is really really spectacular and
it is called caged it's called pre-caged
and the brand is called caged right
um the ingredients here are many they
are Myriad and also they all serve
different purposes so this is able to
function as a best pre-workout in a
really wide variety of situations that's
why I was such a really big fan of it so
to start off with like why it's the best
overall the answer is that it has
various ingredients all of us can exist
different types of workouts so for
example we mentioned endurance workouts
because this is also like the best for
up in germs that's a beta Allen which I
mentioned earlier which is uh very
closely associated to its benefits for
cardiovascular performance but in
addition to that there is also beta in
anhydrous which might sound a bit weird
but that's a natural component it's
found in the beets and it's like some
leafy greens as well and what we've
found in some research is that bathing
anhydrous can help with power so while
that does have applications to like say
squats and bench press and they're
having studies on those that also just
has a lot to do with like sprinting as
well so you may be aware that a lot of
folks a lot of women do high intensity
interval training which is to say they
do like Sprints jogs Sprints jogs
because there's some research that's
best for fat loss this can help with
that so in that regard it can help with
that sort of endurance workout and also
with the better Allen you can help with
like longer term workouts as well in
addition to that there are some Branch
chain amino acids in here Branch chain
amino acids are ones most closely
associated with what's called muscle
protein synthesis basically putting
branched amino acids into a product
having it before your workout
there is some evidence that can help to
keep you from losing muscle throughout
the workout and also can help to kind of
uh maintain energy a little bit
throughout the workout as well so all of
these reasons uh why we named this as
the best pre-workout for endurance the
best workout overall I mean there's also
other ingredients in here that are
interesting like for Focus which can
also for endurance to be honest like
tyrosine and taurine I know focus is
kind of like a nebulous term with
tyrosine for instance basically uh when
you're having a very stressful intense
workout or a long lasting workout it's
pretty easy for the brain to sort of run
out of or run low on neurotransmitters
that help you stay on task tyrosine
might help you to produce more and
thereby stay more focused during longer
workouts so that has applications for
endurance as well other reasons why it's
the best overall is very interestingly
this contains vegetables this is very
strange for a pre-workout but what this
has what's called the total orac blend
from Spectra and if you're familiar with
green superfood powders this is like a
very common supplement out there in more
that's more on the multivitamin side of
things green spiders are basically a way
of delivering antioxidants and some
other components depending on the brand
and the reason why that's been wrapped
into here is that a dose of antioxidants
can help to potentially reduce
inflammation or limit inflammation and
thereby help with like recovery and just
generally contribute to your overall
health there's also some creatine
there's also some citrulline the like
the Mainstays and pre-workouts that I
mentioned earlier all of this is why
it's a really well-rounded product
whatever kind of workout you're doing it
can help contribute to it and as a nice
bonus we think it's the best tasting
pre-workout as well there's orange crush
there's crisp apple there's berry blast
there's like seven different really
tasty flavors and it's also pretty
inexpensive so when you're trying to
judge the cost of a pre-workout it's a
little bit difficult but also a little
bit simple in that there's a really wide
variety of ingredients and dosages in
different products in the industry right
so for what this product has we found
out to be very good value it's really
potently dosed there are a ton of
pre-workouts that don't hit the doses of
the ingredients that's suggested by the
science so while there are cheaper
pre-workers out there as far as value
for money and accurate and effective
dosing we found pre-cage to be to be the
best value this is going to cost about
225 cents a serving one last thing I
want to say about pre-cage though is
that it is pretty high in caffeine so as
I mentioned earlier your average cold
brew 160 milligrams of caffeine one
serving of this is going to be 274
milligrams if 274 milligrams of caffeine
sounds very high to you what you can do
is just half the serving like have half
of a scoopier half a serving especially
if you're a female athlete who tend to
weigh less than male athletes you're
still going to get effective doses of
just about everything else so uh I would
encourage to get this guy it's going to
be obviously half the cost per serving
as well if you're having half a scoop at
a time it's going to last longer as well
try that out and then if you find that
half a scoop isn't too much caffeine it
shouldn't be if you drink coffee then
you can slowly build up if you feel like
it but it's really good value it's got a
really wide range really well dosed
ingredients and it's really freaking
tasty that's a lot I've said about
pre-cage but uh we like it a lot and
I've consumed more than one tub of this
in my lifetime let's talk about another
product though and this one is a good
addition if you still don't like the
idea of taking powdered caffeine I've
given a lot of reasons why it's actually
fine but if you don't want to the
runner-up for the best pre-workout and
also the best pre-workout without
caffeine is Wolverines per it actually
is a really well darsed and effective
product and if there's one takeaway you
can take in this video it's that pouted
up caffeine a bit of Ellen it doesn't
need to be gendered right like even
though it has a name like that it
doesn't mean that it is just the guys or
anything is just for girls uh this is a
solid product and there's no caffeine in
it all so as I mentioned like a lot of
times now caffeine is usually the only
stimulant you're going to get in a
pre-workout there are some that have
like your himbe and stuff but that's
another story usually it's just caffeine
take the caffeine out you've got a bunch
of ingredients that could very well uh
improve your workout without like making
you really wired and making it difficult
to sleep late at night if that's a
concern for you like if you if you have
previous positions to uh insomnia or
anxiety that kind of stuff uh swathering
could be a very good pick here I should
probably say again that I'm not a doctor
you should talk to your doctor but you
know if you have issues with caffeine
obviously getting a caffeine free one
should be an uncontroversial approach to
your pre-workout nutrition but there's
still a lot of good stuff in here right
um I've already mentioned these uh
ingredients before but citrulline beta
alanine beta in the one that comes from
beets that might help with power and
sprinting that's in there as well
there's some taurine which can also help
with focus and there's also Siberian
ginseng which is interesting that one
that type of ginseng it's not usually
it's not really considered a stimulant
it's more like an adaptogen that can
help to kind of combat fatigue in
stressful situations I eat a workout as
opposed to being a stimulant so most
people should be able to take a take
this product and have any issues
sleeping some people might have trouble
with ginseng and sleep but there's a lot
of research also saying that it helps
you sleep so it's kind of like
everyone's very individual here and
that's a really important thing to take
away from that I found honestly if
you're worried about weird ingredients
and pre-workouts so Wolverines is a
really good option because yeah there's
there's no caffeine here everything's
pretty well dosed and uh to make things
better there's no artificial flavors or
sweeteners or ingredients at all in this
as well there's a bit of Splenda in
pre-ked this one is all natural it's
sweetened with stevia so lot of women
and a lot of people find Wolverines
pre-workout to be be more approachable
than other ones so that's why this was
our runner-up and also definitely the
best without caffeine as well I've kind
of said a lot a lot of sciency things in
this video so if it's getting it to be a
bit much we have a written version of
this article as well that you can check
out so if you want to go through this
all at your own pace uh really like read
through everything we've said you can
check out the studies as well because we
cite all the studies for the stuff that
we're seeing if you want to do that read
the full written article I definitely
encourage you to Google it just go to
Google do bar Bend best pre-workout for
women and this article will pop right up
for now we got the best weightless
pre-workout the best free workout for
weight loss which is also the best we
work out for running in our opinion is
transparent Labs lean this is a really
interesting company I like it a lot
because transparent Labs there are there
are a lot of pre-workouts and
supplements in the industry that are not
transparent they're opaque like they
will say they contain these ingredients
but they won't say how much of each
ingredient they contain and they do that
under the guise of we're trying to
preserve our secret recipes so no one
can copy it usually what it really means
is that they want to include less than
effective doses like one milligram of
like I mentioned Ellie that's not really
going to do anything they'll do stuff
like that put in small amounts of stuff
it'll save money and you still get to
put it on the label and say that you
have it transparent Labs doesn't do that
uh very transparent and what's cool as
well is if you go to the website they'll
not only say the precise amount of each
ingredient but they'll also link to
studies for each of them saying why they
put it in there and uh what side they're
basing that on so it's a very like
trustworthy brand I really like
transparent Labs another potentially
cool thing about transparent Labs is
there's no artificial flavors or
sweetness in this one either so if
you're someone who's looking to limit
that kind of stuff you'll be comfortable
with this now why is it the best of
weight loss well you might have noticed
that's called lean now this is not a
weightless product the number one most
important thing if you're looking to
lose weight is to eat fewer calories
than you burn right not way fewer but
the only way that a peso can lose weight
is if they work at how many calories
they burn in a day and then consume a
little bit less than that over a long
period of time right if someone loses
weight and they're not tracking their
calories it's because they are just
happening to eat fewer calories than
they burn whether it's like cutting out
a food group or you know eating fuel
meals or whatever it's all about
calories so to get that out of the way
that's how you actually lose weight but
there are some products out there that
contain ingredients that have some other
interesting ways for potentially coaxing
the body into into like losing more fat
and that sort of thing so the
transparent lab is lean you might notice
it's called lean the main reason for
this being a good pre-workout for weight
loss in addition to it just being a very
good pre-workout meaning it'll probably
let you work out harder do more reps get
in more work have more work capacity run
for longer than if you hadn't had it so
that makes it a good product if you're
trying to lose weight but also this
contains a L-Carnitine a set of
L-Carnitine HCI and there's some
interesting research suggesting that
this can increase fat oxidation so
basically the idea is that with a settle
L-Carnitine it can potentially coax the
body into burning more fat than it would
have otherwise so generally we burn
either stored up carbohydrates glycogen
or sort up fat for energy when we're
exercising and El carnitine some
research suggests that it can help more
fats be burned for energy like it can
help to get it mobilized with the
mitochondria it's all of it come
complicated but like the point here is
research suggests fat oxidation may
increase with the climate so that's why
this is called lean and that's why this
is our best pre-workout for weight loss
for running a very interesting reason
why this is good for running again this
does have all the general endurance
related pre-workout ingredients we've
mentioned in other ones where this gets
the edge though like where it's like
even better than other workouts that
also have better alanine and beta in and
citrulline is that this contains two
different types of caffeine so you've
got 180 milligrams of caffeine which is
like a not not too much like I mentioned
before like this that's less than a 16
ounce coffee from most coffee places but
there's also a small amount of What's
called the patented name is infinity
it's caffeine diamalate what that means
is the caffeine breaks down more slowly
so you will have the 180 milligrams of
caffeine at the beginning of the workout
but there's also a portion of the
caffeine that is going to break down
more slowly so what that does is number
one the idea is for it to prevent a big
energy Spike and crash it's meant to
like happen more gradually and number
two because it digests more slowly the
effect of the caffeine is going to last
for longer so if you are a big Runner
the composition here of two different
types of caffeine while still not
exceeding 220 milligrams total that
should indeed help to help to provide
some more sustained energy over a longer
period of time especially when combined
with other ingredients that are designed
for endurance like the branched amino
acids and the beta alanine so uh very
good product pretty tasty best Runners
and best of weight loss lastly the best
women's pre-workout for muscle gain huge
supplements wrecked the ingredients are
very very good if gaining muscle is your
primary concern here gaining muscle the
most important thing is to consume more
calories than you buy that one is
consuming more calories than you burn
not too much more make sure you're
getting plenty of protein as well that
stuff's all quite complicated but the
calories is the most important part of
getting muscle however we really like
this one for gaining muscle because it
is it's very very strongly dosed if
you're trying to gain muscle you're
eating plenty of calories and plenty of
carbohydrates so generally you can have
like more intense workouts and more
longer lasting workouts and a supplement
like this can really helps you give you
the edge in that regard right like so
you're not low on calories you're not
low on carbohydrates you're having a
really good full-bodied nice workout and
these ones here like they're giving you
eight grams of citrulline most of these
other ones are 506. you're getting three
and a half grams of beta alanine like a
lot of these just do like 1.6 to 2 grams
and it sort of goes on like that like
it's very well dosed for a particularly
intense workout uh in addition to that
there's other ingredients ingredients
like lion's mane mushroom powder which
is an adaptogen that can help the body
to combat fatigue but also there's like
some evidence can help with the
cognitive function as well another thing
I really like is there's a bit of sodium
in this a lot of athletes including
female athletes like Stephie Cohen they
swear by having a little bit of sodium
before you work out if you sweat you're
losing sodium that's why your sweat is
salty and taking some sodium before a
workout there's a ton of evidence that
can help with actually help with
hydration and help with performance so
it's a bit of sodium in here and again
like really good doses of everything
else there is quite a lot of caffeine in
this though uh there's a combination of
caffeine and dicaffeine malate like
transparent Labs except that here it
totals 350 milligrams of caffeine that
is a lot of caffeine but this is so well
dosed like like most of the ingredients
really are very they exceed the
clinically effective doses they do that
just to be safe so no one has any doubt
in their mind they're getting indeed of
citrulline and so on but you especially
if you are on the on the lightest side
like under 200 pounds or under 180
pounds having a half a scoop of this
will give you a pretty normal like
coffee amount of caffeine and you'll
still have pretty effective doses of
everything else as well
so it's a really good one and that's our
list of the best pre-workouts for women
the list ends here I also before I go
just want to address some really common
questions that we get at our
pre-workouts so let's start with what is
a pre-workout right a 12 ounce Colbert
from Starbucks is 155 milligrams of
caffeine right the average speed workout
that I've seen is maybe 180 milligrams
200 milligrams of caffeine so that's
probably gonna be less than 16 ounce
cold brew you know so the caffeine isn't
actually always unbelievably high in
some models they are and we're trying to
not mention those the ones that are more
ideal for people with very large body
weights that are better able to process
that sort of stuff for female athletes
who tend to be on the Lighter Side the
caffeine content it's not going to be as
high as you might imagine it's not like
you're drinking like 10 cups of coffee
worth of caffeine they're actually tend
to be a bit more measured than that the
other question is why take a pre-workout
instead of a cup of coffee and the
answer to that is there are several
ingredients out there that actually are
not stimulants but they still work as
ergogenic AIDS which means they can't
potentially help to increase to improve
performance in workouts so in addition
to caffeine which does indeed have
really specific applications to sports
performance like not just more endurance
but also like more focus more like a
better Reaction Time faster working
memory this sort of stuff all that stuff
can be very useful in a variety of
different sports contexts but in
addition to that you'll often find
ingredients I'll give you a couple of
common ones uh beta alanine is a really
common one the dosages are usually 1.6
to three and a half grams and what beta
Allen has links to is endurance the best
known study on beta alanine showed an
improvement of 2.85 percent in endurance
athletes and if you're an elite athlete
a three percent Improvement is actually
very very significant it's not so crazy
like a 5 000 increase like these aren't
really really dramatic dramatic
overwhelming ingredients again but with
beta alanine Studies have shown if
you're doing strength training in like
the 10 to 20 rep range or if you're
doing bursts of cardiovascular activity
like running or sprinting in the like
one to three minute range yeah you can
see a minor but significant improvement
taking a bit of better alanine and it's
not a stimulant another common
ingredient is citrulline so citrulline
is most closely associated with blood
flow it's a natural ingredient it's an
amino acid that's very common in
watermelon actually citrulline has like
some blood flow also called vasodilation
and so because of that because more
blood is able to flow through your veins
in your vessels that means that more
oxygen can get to the muscles and that
can potentially improve endurance and
also power output as well so there have
been studies on cyclists and on tennis
players like we're not just talking
about like people who are maxing at
deadlift right people who are doing
cycling tennis that sort of stuff there
have been some research to suggest that
taking like five or so grams of
citrulline can help to improve
performance a little bit there as well
and again it's not a stimulant another
one is creatine you'll often find uh
creatine does have the association with
making muscles look a little bit bigger
aesthetically but also there's a lot of
research suggested you can help with
power output so in the lower rep ranges
like say you're doing like one to three
reps of a certain exercise creatine can
help to improve power output there are
some studies showing like 10 maybe more
than 10 increase in in performance
when taking creatine so those are three
common ingredients that are not
stimulants but they can have some
effects on your workout so those are
reasons to some of the reasons why a
pre-workout may have the edge on just a
normal cup of coffee in certain
instances uh one is you know when should
I take it and the answer to that is
basically half an hour before you work
out should be just fine if you have a
really full stomach it'll take a long
time to digest and also you know
workouts aren't super fun on a really
full stomach so ideally you know you
won't have eaten for you know a good
hour uh and you'll have your pre-workout
and about a half hour later things just
start to kick in uh another really
important thing to note about timing
though is that free workouts are a
supplement to help you have an effective
workout supplements mean it's just a
supplement it's a small part of the
overall plan the overall plan is your
total diet your total Nutrition your
total approach to food so you don't want
to be in a really big calorie deficit a
lot of people kind of wind up in a big
calorie deficit because they want to
lose fat and look better and a swimsuit
that kind of thing but going too far in
a calorie deficit and too low in
carbohydrates and too low in protein and
too low in fat any of those especially
all of those will lead to having just a
crummy day probably having nutrient
deficiencies and also not having
effective workouts at all I've had
multiple phds on this topic talk to me
about pre-workout nutrition and they all
say don't forget carbohydrates like have
a meal like eat regularly eat throughout
the day and having a glue about
approaching in carbs in like one to
three hours before you work out that's
going to play a very significant role in
having a useful worker and also just
like
getting the most out of your workout and
also not being miserable all the time
don't just not eat or eat very very
little make sure you're getting your
carbohydrates and make sure you're
getting your protein as well beyond the
pre-workouts you're consuming uh there
are other things to consider as well I
touched this earlier if uh if you if
caffeine tends to wig you out or if you
have like issues with anxiety or
insomnia that kind of stuff there's a
good chance of the caffeinated
pre-workouts might not be for you
fortunately there are uncaffeinated
pre-workouts that you can get uh like
like wolverines
that will help to eliminate that as a
problem but yeah that's one of the
reasons why I scared of social Medical
Professional just in case you have any
you know pre-existing conditions that
kind of stuff that might interfere with
any of these ingredients interestingly
most of these ingredients don't have to
be taken pre-workout the caffeine kind
of does the caffeine like comes on and
has an effect but everything else like
the creatine uh beta alanine the
citrulline the betaine the studies on
these ingredients are people kind of
taking it at any time throughout the day
or a few times throughout the day like
it's more about building up these
ingredients in your body like in your
system so it's like kind of running
around your blood system and that sort
of stuff it's more about it being in
your body than taking it before a
workout and then it like peaking and
kicking in so you can take it before
work out and that's totally fine but
actually if you're not taking caffeine
you can take better alanine baby
essentially in this kind of stuff you
can kind of take it anytime um it's
helpful just to kind of take it before a
workout just because it's then you don't
have to think about it in the morning or
anything but technically timing doesn't
isn't really apply to most of these
ingredients it's mostly the caffeine
maybe a couple other ones the last thing
if I didn't mention this at the
beginning of the video I don't really
remember but beta alanine uh
unbelievably common as a pre-workout
ingredient you should know that it
typically produces a tingling sensation
of this on the skin it's very temporary
it just kind of happens for a little bit
it's completely harmless it's something
to worry about uh some people don't like
it so if you take a pre-workout with
beta alanine in it that has interesting
applications for cardio and endurance
and everything like that just expect the
tingliness if you hate it uh don't take
it again so that's uh that's it that's
our less the best women's pre-workout
it's pretty confident in that list if
you've got prerequisite like yourself
let us know in the comments and also
again if you want to find the full
written article of this you can just
Google bar Bend best pre-workouts for
women and it'll come up and you can just
read it at your own pace otherwise
that's it that's it for me thank you for
watching everybody and I'll see you next
video
[Music]